https://www.whsmith.co.uk/help/our-policies/online-privacy-policy/hel00016/#cookiepolicy

Your browser is currently not set to accept cookies. Please turn this functionality on or check if you have another program set to block cookies.
Close
Refine Your Results By:
Refine by:
Purposes For Which We Will Use Your Personal Data
How Is Your Personal Data Collected?
Data Security
How Long Will You Use my Personal Data For?
WHSmith Privacy Policy
WHSmith.co.uk wants you to be able to shop with confidence on our site, which is why we take the privacy of your personal information very seriously. We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data.
This privacy notice will inform you as to how we look after your personal data when you visit our website (regardless of where you visit it from) and tell you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you. By using our website or any of our services, or providing us with any personal data, you agree to your personal data being used and disclosed in the manner set out in this policy.
Back to top
Purpose of this Privacy Notice
This privacy notice aims to give you information on how WHSmith collects and processes your personal data through your use of this website, including any data you may provide through this website when you shop with us. WH Smith High Street Limited is the data controller and is responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as "WHSmith", "we", "us" or "our" in this privacy notice).
It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.
Back to top
How We Use Your Personal Data
We will only use your personal data (name, address, email address, date of birth) when the law allows us to, and only for the purposes agreed to when you provided it. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:
Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you, i.e. fulfilling an order.
Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
Where we need to comply with a legal or regulatory obligation.
Generally we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data, other than for our own marketing in some situations, and always for third party marketing. In relation to direct marketing communications via email or text message where we collect your consent, you will always be asked to decide how you wish to be contacted. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing (or to object to receiving marketing where we do not rely on consent to send it) at any time by contacting our Customer Services team or by unsubscribing from marketing communications in any e-mail sent to you.
Back to top
Purposes For Which We Will Use Your Personal Data
We will use your personal data:
To register you as a new customer
Process and deliver your order(s) including:
-Managing payments, fees and charges
- Collecting and recovering money owed to us
- Verifying your age when purchasing age sensitive products
To manage our relationship with you which will include:
- Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy
- Asking you to leave a product or service review or take a survey
- Sending you reminders if you abandon (exit the site) after a search, product view, basket or do not complete your order
To enable you to partake in a prize draw or competition**
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, development, support, reporting and hosting of data)
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you**
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you
** These activities require your explicit consent
Back to top
How is Your Personal Data Collected?
We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:
Direct interactions. You may give us your personal information by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you:
- purchase any of our products or services;
- create an account on our website;
- create an account in the WHSmith Scan & Go application on Google Play or iStore
- join our newsletters programmes or other publications;
- enter a competition, promotion or survey;
- give us some feedback
- interact with our social media channels; or
- engage with our external advertising on third party sites.
Automated technologies or interactions. As you interact with our website, newsletters, or emails we may automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies and other similar technologies.
Third parties or publicly available sources. We may collect technical information about your journey through our site with Google Analytics. We and our authorised partners use this data to improve your site experience.
Back to top
Your Legal Rights
You have the right to:
Request to access and receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you;
Request any corrections to the personal data that we hold about you;
Request erasure of your personal data;
Object to processing of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground;
Request restriction of processing of your personal data;
Request the transfer of your personal data to you or to a third party; or
Withdraw consent at any time where we are relying on consent to process your personal data.
You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your access request is manifestly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we may refuse to comply with your request where it is manifestly unfounded, repetitive or excessive.
We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.
Back to top
The Data We Collect About You
Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data).
When you complete an online form, register or shop with us online, register or shop using the Scan & Go application, or engage with us in the ways identified in the ‘How is Your Personal Data Collected?’ section we may collect, use and store different kinds of personal data about you such as your name, gender, date of birth, billing/delivery address, e-mail address and telephone number. We may also collect and retain information about your interactions with us either in store, online, social media, or through our contact centres so that we can process your transactions and deal with any future queries.
We also collect, use and share Aggregated Data such as statistical or demographic data for any purpose. Aggregated Data may be derived from your personal data but is not considered personal data in law as this data does not directly or indirectly reveal your identity. For example, we may aggregate your Usage Data to calculate the percentage of users accessing a specific website feature. However, if we combine or connect Aggregated Data with your personal data so that it can directly or indirectly identify you, we treat the combined data as personal data which will be used in accordance with this privacy notice.
We do not collect any Special Categories of Personal Data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.
Back to top
Consent
In certain situations, we can collect and process your data with your consent.
In limited situations, we may approach you for your written consent to allow us to process certain particularly sensitive data. If we do so, we will provide you with full details of the information that we would like and the reason we need it, so that you can carefully consider whether you wish to consent. You should be aware that it is not a condition of your contract with us that you agree to any request for consent from us.
When collecting your personal data, we'll always make clear to you which data is necessary in connection with a particular contractual or legal requirement.
We may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent (for example, in relation to fraud management or to assist with investigations by the police or other regulatory bodies) in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.
Back to top
Opting Out
You can ask us or third parties to stop sending you marketing messages at any time by contacting us or by unsubscribing from marketing communications in any e-mail sent to you.
In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data by making a 'Request for Erasure'. In order to make such a request, please write to us at support@whsmith.co.uk. Following your request, your personal data shall be removed from our database without undue delay in accordance with statutory requirements. Our DPO shall thereafter take reasonable steps to inform any third parties who may be processing any personal data they hold about you that you have requested the erasure of any links to, or copy or replication of, your personal data.
Back to top
Promotional Offers from Us While You Are On The Website
We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you and display them to you on the website.**
** These activities require your explicit consent.
Back to top
Marketing
We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising. We may send you marketing about our own goods and services if either you have opted in to receive our marketing messages, or you have previously bought or enquired about similar goods or services from us (including by placing items in your basket but not completing an order) and you have not opted out from receiving our marketing messages.
You can, should you wish, unsubscribe to any or all of our marketing material at any time. By clicking the ‘unsubscribe’ link in any email we send, you will be unsubscribed from that programme. You can also contact us at any point to opt out of any or all marketing communications, or do that by visiting the ‘preference centre’ on our site (available from February 2021).
Back to top
Off-Site Marketing
Whilst browsing other websites you may see WHSmith promotional messages, these will be displayed based on cookies placed during your recent visit to our website. Personal information is not used in the delivery of these promotional messages. Please see our Cookie policy for more detail.
Back to top
Third-Party Marketing
You are in control of any information we share with Third Parties for marketing purposes. As you go through our checkout or account creation processes you will be asked to advise us which contacts you wish to receive. If you have opted in to receive marketing from third parties you can opt out of these marketing messages at any time by contacting us or by unsubscribing from marketing communications in any e-mail sent to you.
Back to top
Third-Party Links
Clicking on links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications contained within this website, or enabling those connections, may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy notice of every website you visit.
Back to top
Disclosures of Your Personal Data
We may have to share your personal data with the parties set out below for the purposes set out above (in Purposes for which we will use your Personal Data'):
Other WHSmith group entities, details of which can be found in our Annual Reports;
Third party suppliers in order to fulfil orders placed by you
Trusted technical partners for the purposes of site development and improvements
We may, from time to time, expand, reduce or sell WHSmith and this may involve the transfer of divisions or the whole business to new owners. If this happens, your personal data will, where relevant, be transferred to the new owner or controlling party, under the terms of this Privacy Notice.
We require all third parties to respect the security of your personal data and to treat it in accordance with the law. We do not allow our third-party service providers to use your personal data for their own purposes and only permit them to process your personal data for specified purposes and in accordance with our instructions.
Back to top
International Transfers
Some of our third party processors may transfer your data outside of the EEA. Locations outside of the EEA where your data may be transferred is/are: the United States of America. We will update this Privacy Notice if the named locations change. When we or our third party processors transfer your data outside of the EEA we ensure that it remains subject to appropriate data security arrangements at all times and implement the right safeguards with these processors.
Back to top
Data Security
We have appropriate security measures in place to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, technical partners, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.
We have procedures in place to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.
Back to top
How Long Will You Use my Personal Data For?
We will only retain your personal data for as long as necessary to fulfil the purposes we collected it for, including for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.
To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature, and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal requirements.
In some circumstances we may anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.
Back to top
If You Fail to Provide Your Personal Data
Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.
Back to top
Data Protection Officer
We have appointed a Data Protection Officer ("DPO") who is responsible for overseeing questions in relation to this privacy notice. If you have any questions about this privacy notice, including any requests to exercise your legal rights, please contact Data Protection Officer, WHSmith, Greenbridge Road, Swindon SN3 3LD or e-mail support@whsmith.co.uk.
Back to top
Contacting the Regulator
If you feel that your data has not been handled correctly, or you wish to make a complaint, you have the right to contact the Information Commissioner's Office ("ICO"), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues, at any time. You can contact them by telephone (0303 123 1113) or via their website
(http://www.ico.org.uk/concerns). We would, however, be grateful for the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.
Back to top
General
It is likely that we will need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. We will notify you of any significant changes via our newsletters.
Back to top
Cookie Policy
Cookies are small text files. Many websites place cookies on your computer when you visit. Cookies are used to make websites work, or to make them work more efficiently, and to provide useful information to website operators.
Many web browsers allow users to control most cookies through their browser settings. However doing so will prevent the checkout from working and you will not be able to place orders.
Back to top
Your Cookie Preferences
We use different types of cookies to optimise your experience on our website. Read more about the different types of cookies below to learn more about their purpose. You can change your cookie permissions at any time. Remember that disabling cookies may affect your experience on the website.
Essential Cookies
These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with the services available through our websites and to use some of its features, such as access to secure areas.
An example of an essential cookie: __cfduid
Performance Cookies
These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our websites but are non-essential to their use. However, without these cookies, certain functionality (like videos) may become unavailable.
An example of a performance cookie: _gat_UA-533522-1
Marketing Cookies
These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests.
An example of a marketing cookie: uuid
Unclassified Cookies
These are cookies that have not yet been categorised. We are in the process of classifying these cookies with the help of their providers.
Back to top
Managing Cookies
You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly. Find out more about how to manage your cookies by browser below.
Manage In Chrome
Manage In Internet Explorer
Manage In Safari
Manage In Firefox
Back to top
The Cookies We Use and What They Do
The table here explains what cookies we use and why. More information about cookies, including details on viewing what cookies have been set and how to delete them is available at allaboutcookies.org.
Name
Technical Name
Purpose
Retention Period
__cfduid	 	__cfduid	 	The cookie is set by CloudFare. The cookie is used to identify individual clients behind a shared IP address and apply security settings on a per-client basis. It does not correspond to any user ID in the web application and does not store any personally identifiable information.	 	1 month
dwac_abf46f84d5e4b81be4f560ffc6	 	dwac_abf46f84d5e4b81be4f560ffc6	 	Stores the following data for analytics purposes: Session ID, report suite name, shopper’s customer ID, source code group ID (encoded), currency mnemonic, and time zone. The * in the cookie name is a value unique to the site.	 	Current session
cqcid	 	cqcid	 	Hashed ID for an unregistered shopper.	 	Current session
sid	 	sid	 	Identifies the current browsing session. The Salesforce Reference Architecture (SFRA) uses this to determine whether to display the cookie hint content asset. Only used by SFRA and by customizations.	 	Current session
dwanonymous_9a189b88225228e55647ec94df1b6997	 	dwanonymous_9a189b88225228e55647ec94df1b6997	 	Random ID used to identify an unregistered shopper or a shopper who has not yet logged in independent of the session. For example, this is used to track basket and order activity and for analytics. It is not used for any activity that occurs after the shopper registers an account. The * in the cookie name is a value unique to the site.	 	5 months
__cq_dnt	 	__cq_dnt	 	Indicates that the browser has opted out of CC Einstein tracking for this site. Commerce Cloud sets it with each page response based on the value of the corresponding session attribute TrackingAllowed. The value of this cookie always matches that of the Storefront dw_dnt* cookie.	 	10 years
dw_dnt*	 	dw_dnt*	 	Controls client-side JavaScript for Commerce Cloud tracking features (Analytics, Einstein, and ActiveData). Commerce Cloud sets it with each page response, based on the value of the corresponding session attribute TrackingAllowed. The value of this cookie always matches that of the Einstein __cq_dnt cookie.	 	Current session
dwsid	 	dwsid	 	Identifies the current browsing session.	 	Current session
dw	 	dw	 	This cookie has been deprecated and is no longer used to collect data. It is in the process of being removed from the SiteGenesis codebase.	 	Current session
dw_cookies_accepted	 	dw_cookies_accepted	 	When the merchant has enabled the cookie hint notice, it records that the shopper has acknowledged that cookies are being used.For more information, see SiteGenesis Standards Compliance.	 	Current session
wcsid	 	wcsid	 	This cookie is set by Olark live chat software. The cookie is a session identifier that is used to keep track of a single at session.
hblid	 	hblid	 	The cookie is set by Olark live chat software and is used as a visitor identifier to remember a visitor between visits.	 	2 years
_oklv	 	_oklv	 	The cookie is set by Olark live chat software. According to Olark documentation, the cookie is the Olark Loader version used for improved caching.
uuid	 	uuid	 	Third-party version of the first-party __cq_uuid cookie set on .cquotient.com. Contains a randomly generated user ID. Used to track data for analytics purposes, including Commerce Cloud's own analytics as described in the Trust & Compliance documentation, such as Commerce Cloud Reports and Dashboards.	 	13 months
_gcl_au	 	_gcl_au	 	This cookie is used by Google Analytics to understand user interaction with the website.	 	2 months
MUID	 	MUID	 	Used by Microsoft as a unique identifier. The cookie is set by embedded Microsoft scripts. The purpose of this cookie is to synchronize the ID across many different Microsoft domains to enable user tracking.	 	1 year
_okdetect	 	_okdetect	 	This cookie is set by Olark live chat software. The cookie is used for detecting when storage contexts have changed due to things like ssl or host transitions.	 	Necessary
__cq_uuid	 	__cq_uuid	 	First-party version of the third-party uuid cookie. Contains a randomly generated user ID. Used to collect information about the shopper's activities on the merchant's own website. This information is also used for analytics purposes, including by Commerce Cloud Reports and Dashboards.	 	13 months
_ga	 	_ga	 	This cookie is installed by Google Analytics. The cookie is used to calculate visitor, session, campaign data and keep track of site usage for the site's analytics report. The cookies store information anonymously and assign a randomly generated number to identify unique visitors.	 	2 years
_gid	 	_gid	 	This cookie is installed by Google Analytics. The cookie is used to store information of how visitors use a website and helps in creating an analytics report of how the wbsite is doing. The data collected including the number visitors, the source where they have come from, and the pages viisted in an anonymous form.	 	1 day
mp_whsmith_mixpanel	 	mp_whsmith_mixpanel
1 year
_cs_c	 	_cs_c	 	allows to record the user consent	 	13 months
_cs_id	 	_cs_id	 	Includes user ID	 	13 months (according to the default value, but it can be administered on the account)
_cs_s	 	_cs_s	 	Includes number of pages viewed in the current session. Then, it is followed either by ".0", by ".1" (to include a visitor to their complete session recording service: HTML background and all mouse movements) or by ".2" (to include a visitor for Session Replay recording service).	 	30 minutes
_fbp	 	_fbp	 	This cookie is set by Facebook to deliver advertisement when they are on Facebook or a digital platform powered by Facebook advertising after visiting this website.	 	2 months
_gat_UA-533522-1	 	_gat_UA-533522-1	 	This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.	 	1 minute
_gat_UA-533522-6	 	_gat_UA-533522-6	 	This is a pattern type cookie set by Google Analytics, where the pattern element on the name contains the unique identity number of the account or website it relates to. It appears to be a variation of the _gat cookie which is used to limit the amount of data recorded by Google on high traffic volume websites.	 	1 minute
fr	 	fr	 	The cookie is set by Facebook to show relevant advertisments to the users and measure and improve the advertisements. The cookie also tracks the behavior of the user across the web on sites that have Facebook pixel or Facebook social plugin.	 	2 months
olfsk	 	olfsk	 	This cookie is set by Olark live chat software. This cookies is a storage identifier used to maintain chat state across pages.	 	2 years
_okbk	 	_okbk	 	The cookie is set by Olark live chat software and is used to store extra state information of the chat box.
_ok	 	_ok	 	The cookie is set by Olark live chat software and is used to store most recent Olark site for security purposes.
IDE	 	IDE	 	Used by Google DoubleClick and stores information about how the user uses the website and any other advertisement before visiting the website. This is used to present users with ads that are relevant to them according to the user profile.	 	1 year
Back to top
1 - 8
of
8
Results
Help Center
Sort by
Popularity
We value your privacy
By clicking 'Accept' you are agreeing to our use of cookies for content personalisation, analytics, navigation and marketing purposes. To find out more about how WHSmith use cookies
Read our cookie policy.
Accept Cookies
Your Cookie Preferences
We use different types of cookies to optimize your experience on our website. Click on the categories
below to learn more about their purpose. You can change your cookie permissions at any time. Remember
that disabling cookies may affect your experience on the website. Please read our Cookie Policy.
Essential Cookies
These cookies are strictly necessary to provide you with the services available through our websites and
to use some of its features, such as access to secure areas.
An example of an essential cookie: __cfduid
Performance Cookies
These cookies are used to enhance the performance and functionality of our websites but are
non-essential to their use. However, without these cookies, certain functionality (like videos) may
become unavailable.
An example of an performance cookie: _gat_UA-533522-1
Marketing Cookies
These cookies are used to make advertising messages more relevant to you. They perform functions like
preventing the same ad from continuously reappearing, ensuring that ads are properly displayed for
advertisers, and in some cases selecting advertisements that are based on your interests.
An example of an marketing cookie: uuid
Unclassified Cookies
These are cookies that have not yet been categorized. We are in the process of classifying these cookies
with the help of their providers.
